[](#privacy-policy-and-cookie-policy)Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy
---------------------------------------------------------------------

Please note: The English translation of the Blacklane Privacy Policy is provided for the convenience of our non-German-speaking customers. Regardless of this, only the original German-language version is legally binding.

### **[](#privacy-policy)Privacy Policy**

1. [Scope](#Scope)
2. [Name and Contact Information of the Controller](#NameandContactInformationoftheController)
3. [Contact Information for the Data Protection Officer](#ContactInformationfortheDataProtectionOfficer)
4. [Data Security](#DataSecurity)
5. [Provision of the websites](#Provisionofthewebsites)
6. [Cookies, pixels and similar technologies](#Cookiespixelsandsimilartechnologies)
7. [Special Features for the Blacklane Apps](#SpecialFeaturesfortheBlacklaneApps)
8. [Social Media/Social Networks](#SocialMediaSocialNetworks)
9. [Data Processing During Registered Use of Blacklane Services and Booking Rides](#DataProcessingDuringRegisteredUseofBlacklaneServicesandBookingRides)
10. [Payment & Fraud Prevention](#PaymentandFraudPrevention)
11. [Communication with Blacklane](#CommunicationwithBlacklane)
12. [E-mail Advertising, Newsletter](#EmailAdvertisingNewsletter)
13. [Involvement of Data Processors by Blacklane](#InvolvementofDataProcessorsbyBlacklane)
14. [Rights of Data Subjects](#RightsofDataSubjects)
15. [Automated decisions](#Automateddecisions)
16. [Data Erasure and Storage Duration](#DataErasureandStorageDuration)
17. [Amendment or Update of this Privacy Policy](#AmendmentorUpdateofthisPrivacyPolicy)

### **[](#BlacklaneCookiePolicy)[](#cookie-policy)Cookie Policy**

1. [Adjust](#Adjust)
2. [Adnxs (AppNexus)](#Adnxs)
3. [Bing Ads](#Bing)
4. [DoubleClick](#DoubleClick)
5. [Facebook (Custom Audiences und Impressions)](#FacebookCustomAudiencesundImpressions)
6. [Google Ads (former Google AdWords Conversion Tracker)](#GoogleAds)
7. [Google Analytics](#GoogleAnalytics)
8. [Google Dynamic Remarketing](#GoogleDynamicRemarketing)
9. [Google Firebase](#GoogleFirebase)
10. [Google Fonts](#GoogleFonts)
11. [Google reCAPTCHA](#GooglereCAPTCHA)
12. [Google Tag Manager and Conversion Link](#GoogleTagManagerandConversionLink)
13. [Hotjar](#Hotjar)
14. [Intercom](#Intercom)
15. [LinkedIn Marketing Solutions](#LinkedInMarketingSolutions)
16. [Mailchimp](#Mailchimp)
17. [Mixpanel](#Mixpanel)
18. [Nexmo](#Nexmo)
19. [Optimizely](#Optimizely)
20. [Outbrain Pixel / OutBrain Amplify](#Outbrain)
21. [Polyfill](#Polyfill)
22. [Raygun](#Raygun)
23. [Rudderstack](#Rudderstack)
24. [Salesforce](#Salesforce)
25. [Sendgrid](#Sendgrid)
26. [Snowplow](#Snowplow)
27. [Twitter Advertising](#Twitter)
28. [Xandr](#Xandr)

[](#a-id-scope)1\. Scope
------------------------

We, Blacklane GmbH ("Blacklane"), take the protection of your personal data seriously and protect your privacy when processing them in accordance with the applicable data protection regulations.

This privacy policy informs you as a visitor of the Blacklane websites, as a user or customer of the online platform of Blacklane, a Blacklane App or other services of Blacklane (together also "Blacklane Services") which of your personal data is processed by Blacklane and for which purpose. The Blacklane Services are not aimed at minors.

Information on the processing of personal data of chauffeurs can be found in the [Chauffeur Privacy Policy](https://partner.blacklane.com/s/en/chauffeur-privacy-policy/) (e.g. in the BL Chauffeur App).

[](#a-id-nameandcontactinformationofthecontroller)2\. Name and Contact Information of the Controller
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

The controller for the processing of data within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is:

**Blacklane GmbH** Feurigstrasse 59 10827 Berlin Germany E-Mail: [info@blacklane.com](mailto:info@blacklane.com)

You can find further information on Blacklane in the [Legal Notice](https://www.blacklane.com/en/imprint/)

[](#a-id-contactinformationforthedataprotectionofficer)3\. Contact Information for the Data Protection Officer
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Our data protection officer is:

Bernhard Kloos, HK2 Comtection GmbH, Hausvogteiplatz 11 A, 10117 Berlin

You can contact our data protection officer confidentially by mail to the above-mentioned address. Alternatively, you can contact our data protection officer and our data protection crew by e-mail to: [dataprotection@blacklane.com](mailto:dataprotection@blacklane.com).

[](#a-id-datasecurity)4\. Data Security
---------------------------------------

Blacklane uses appropriate technical and organizational security measures to ensure a level of protection for personal data appropriate to the risk, taking into account the state of the art, implementation costs and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing as well as the risk of varying likelihood and the degree of risk. The transfer of personal data between your end device and Blacklane is generally carried out in an encrypted form (TLS encryption). You can identify an encrypted connection for example by the lock symbol in the address line of your browser.

If you communicate with us by e-mail, access by third parties cannot be ruled out. Blacklane also uses transport encryption for e-mails in general. But in the case of confidential information, Blacklane recommends using the postal way or fully encrypted e-mail communication (PGP). Please let us know if you would like to correspond with us by e-mail in an encrypted form so that we can give you information on the relevant addresses and public keys.

[](#a-id-provisionofthewebsites)5\. Provision of the websites
-------------------------------------------------------------

When visiting Blacklane websites for information purposes, i.e. even without your registration, data is automatically collected regarding the usage through your browser (hereinafter “surf data”). This includes your IP address, the status code, the Blacklane websites visited, date and time of the server request, browser type and browser version, referrer (website visited beforehand), files transferred and data volume. The surf data is stored by Blacklane in so-called log files. If you visit Blacklane websites without having a Blacklane account, we will not know who you are.

We inform you about the cookies and analysis services used by Blacklane in section 6. Otherwise, your surf data will not be provided to third parties. The processing of surf data is mainly carried out to establish and maintain the technical connection when surfing the internet. This data is also used by Blacklane in a pseudonymized or anonymized form in order to analyze the use of our websites, to design and improve the Blacklane services to meet demand, to recognize and eliminate technical or process-related disruptions and problems and to prevent illegal use of the Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks).

Stored log files are erased or anonymized, provided they are no longer required to ensure the general functionality of Blacklane services. Blacklane retains the log files only insofar as you have consented to this or if there are legal retention obligations.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when providing websites is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest). Insofar you are a Blacklane user or customer, the legal basis is also Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO (contract performance, see otherwise below [number 9](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#DataProcessingDuringRegisteredUseofBlacklaneServicesandBookingRides).). If you have consented to an extended usage of your surf data, the legal basis is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. a GDPR (your consent). You can revoke your consent at any time.

[](#a-id-cookiespixelsandsimilartechnologies)6\. Cookies, pixels and similar technologies
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

When using Blacklane services, cookies, pixels or similar methods may be used. This is common for most large websites.

Cookies are small text files and pixels are small graphic files which can be stored on the user's end device. You will find comprehensive information on the cookies, pixels and similar methods used by Blacklane in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#BlacklaneCookiePolicy).

As part of your use of Blacklane Services, Blacklane sets the cookies that are necessary for Blacklane to provide a feature you request (e.g., language, login status, cookie consent). Blacklane also uses, where you have consented, its own and third party cookies to analyze and improve the use of the Blacklane Services, to improve and personalize functionality to you, to detect and correct malfunctions and problems of a technical or process nature, to prevent unlawful use of the Blacklane Services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyber-attacks) and for marketing purposes. (including the measurement, analysis and evaluation of advertising). The details of this can be found in our Cookie Policy. Your consent to the setting and use of cookies by Blacklane is documented electronically via a Consent Management Tool or Consent Management Platform (CMP) used by Blacklane. You can revoke your consent at any time with future effect or change your cookie settings; the easiest way to do this is to change your cookie settings as you wish in the CMP used by Blacklane.

Additionally, you can prevent the storage of cookies and delete existing cookies at any time in the settings of your browser. However, this may lead to the fact that individual functions of the Blacklane Services are not or only partially available. The storage period varies per cookie and can be viewed in your browser in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#BlacklaneCookiePolicy).

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using cookies, pixels and similar procedures are Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a (your consent) and lit. f DSGVO (legitimate interest of Blacklane in case of necessary cookies in connection with § 25 TTDSG).

[](#a-id-specialfeaturesfortheblacklaneapps)7\. Special Features for the Blacklane Apps
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Blacklane’s apps are another access point to Blacklane services. Similar processing of personal data is generally carried out via the Blacklane apps as via the Blacklane websites (see [number 5](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#Provisionofthewebsites) above) or in the case of registered use of the Blacklane Services (see [number 9](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#DataProcessingDuringRegisteredUseofBlacklaneServicesandBookingRides)).

When using the Blacklane apps, Blacklane may also access additional data in relation to the app or to your end device, such as e.g. the device name, device manufacturer, model, operating system, app or SDK version, mode.

There are also push notifications in the Blacklane apps, i.e. notifications provided by Blacklane in the app of your end device. You will only receive push notifications if you have given your consent to this on your end device. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (your consent).

There is a special Blacklane App ("BL Chauffeur") for drivers or driving service providers working with Blacklane. You can find information on the processing of personal data carried out by means of BL Chauffeur in the [Chauffeur Privacy Policy](https://partner.blacklane.com/s/en/chauffeur-privacy-policy/).

[](#a-id-socialmediasocialnetworks)8\. Social Media / Social Networks
---------------------------------------------------------------------

### [](#8.1-blacklane-s-social-media-presence)8.1 Blacklane’s Social Media Presence

Blacklane maintains pages in social networks such as Twitter, LinkedIn or Facebook. The respective provider of the social network provides detailed information about which personal data is processed and how. In addition, please see our notes on our pages on the respective platforms.

### [](#8.2-facebook-facebook-messenger-and-facebook-connect)8.2 Facebook, Facebook Messenger and Facebook Connect

Blacklane uses services of the social network, Facebook operated by Meta Platforms Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). The controller for the data processing in Europe for Facebook is Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. You can access Facebook’s data protection information here: [](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)[https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)

You can contact us and exchange messages with Blacklane via **Facebook Messenger**.

Blacklane also provides the option of logging in to the Blacklane account using **Facebook Connect**. In order to do this, you will be sent to a Facebook page where you may log in using your Facebook user information. If you log in to the Blacklane account using Facebook Connect, certain personal data will be transferred by Facebook to Blacklane. Facebook will inform you regarding what data will be transferred, for the purpose of which you may grant or refuse explicit consent. Personal data will not be transferred by Facebook to Blacklane without this consent. Facebook can also determine from your login via Facebook Connect that you have logged in with us and when you have done so. Blacklane uses the data transmitted by Facebook in order to identify you.

\_\_If you actively choose to log in via Facebook, you consent to Blacklane processing, in a personalized form, the data transmitted by Facebook to identify you in connection with your account. This consent may be revoked at any time without any additional costs and with effect for the future. \_\_

You also have the option at any time to adjust the usage of Facebook Connect and log in to your Blacklane account in another manner.

Blacklane uses, where you have consented to this, **Facebook Custom Audiences** from lists to show you targeted advertising via Facebook. Blacklane creates lists of existing contacts and uploads them to Facebook via Blacklane's Facebook account. Before uploading, the list is hashed locally in the browser and only then sent to Facebook. There it is compared with Facebook's existing list of hashed IDs of Facebook users. The matches are then added to Blacklane's Custom Audience. Facebook does not collect any new personal data.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using Facebook Connect is in each case Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (your consent).

We will inform you in our [Cookie Policy](#BlacklaneCookiePolicy) about Facebook’s cookies, pixels and similar technologies which are used by Blacklane.

### [](#8.3-google-customer-match)8.3 Google Customer Match

Blacklane uses the Customer Match service of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

At Google Customer Match, Blacklane creates lists of existing contacts and uploads them to Google via Blacklane's Google Account. Before uploading, the list is hashed locally in the browser with the SHA256 algorithm and only then transmitted to Google with TLS encryption. There it is compared with existing Google Accounts. The matches are then added to the Blacklane Audience. On this basis we can display targeted advertising via Google Ads.

The legal basis for processing personal data when using Google Customer Match is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR (your consent).

We will inform you about cookies and similar procedures of Google, which are used by Blacklane, in our [Cookie Policy](#BlacklaneCookiePolicy).

[](#a-id-dataprocessingduringregistereduseofblacklaneservicesandbookingrides)9\. Data Processing During Registered Use of Blacklane Services and Booking Rides
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Blacklane processes the following personal data provided by you when you register and use Blacklane Services or when you book rides (hereinafter “customer data”).

* Personal master data (form of address, title, first name, last name, company, address, zip code, place, country, password);
* Contact data (e.g. telephone number, cellphone number, e-mail address);
* Contract data (e.g. time and manner of registration, status)
* Ride-related data (e.g. pickup location, destination, times, flight number, special requests).
* Status (e.g. bonus program), customer history (e.g. previous rides);
* Contract invoicing (e.g. invoices, status, invoicing address) and payment data (e.g. last 4 digits of the credit card number).

The customer data will be used for Blacklane services, i.e. for the personalized fulfillment of the framework agreement after registration (creation, storage, administration and support of your Blacklane account), for the procurement of booked rides and for the fulfillment of the contract of carriage for the benefit of the customer with the limousine service provider. Blacklane provides customer data to third parties, if necessary, in particular to the limousine service providers so that the customer can be transported in accordance with their booking and the transport can be processed. If the customer has indicated a bonus program supported by Blacklane, the data required in this regard is transmitted to the bonus program provider. The payment data collected is stored via a payment service provider and transferred to the intermediary financial service provider or bank (see [Point 10](#PaymentandFraudPrevention)).

Personal data can be transmitted to limousine service providers in a third-party country outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area in which the transport is intended to take place. Blacklane cannot generally provide further information on the data protection level in the third-party country. An adequacy decision (see Art. 45 Paragraph 3 GDPR) or suitable guarantees (see Art. 46 GDPR) are not required for the transmission since the transmission is required for the performance of a contract between the data subject and the controller or to carry out pre-contractual measures upon request from the data subject (Art. 49 Paragraph 1 lit b GDPR) or because the transmission is required to enter into or to perform a contract concluded in the interest of the data subject by the controller with another natural or legal person (Art. 49 Paragraph 1 lit c GDPR).

Customers have the possibility to rate a ride arranged by Blacklane e.g. in the Blacklane App. Ratings are stored in the customer's profile and can be communicated to the respective driving service or provider or chauffeur in anonymised form. The customer can view his own reviews, other customers will not see these reviews. The purpose of the data processing within the evaluation system is the handling of the trip or the payment towards the driver or the dispatcher as well as the analysis and improvement of the Blacklane Services, e.g. to monitor the proper execution of trips, to increase the quality and to prevent or combat illegal use. Ratings are usually not stored for more than 2 years and then deleted or anonymised.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data during the registered use of Blacklane Services and during the booking of trips is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR (contract performance). If the data subject provides additional, voluntary information (e.g. flight number, frequent flyer programme, special requests, rating), the legal basis is their consent according to Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR and our legitimate interest according to Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. f GDPR.

In addition, Blacklane processes customer data in order to analyse the use of the Blacklane Services, to design and improve them in a demand-oriented and personalised manner, to advertise the Blacklane Services, to detect, limit and eliminate malfunctions and problems of a technical or process-related nature and to prevent illegal use of the Blacklane Services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). In this respect, the legal basis for the processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane). Data will not be passed on to recipients in this respect unless to Blacklane's data processors (see Art. 28 GDPR) or as far as otherwise permitted by law.

[](#a-id-paymentandfraudprevention)10\. Payment & Fraud Prevention
------------------------------------------------------------------

### [](#10.1-payment)10.1 Payment

All Blacklane bookings can be paid by credit or debit card. The credit card information only has to be stored once upon the first booking and is protected against unauthorized access. For this purpose, a certified payment provider is used whose systems meet the applicable security standards, such as the PCI DSS standard (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard). For recurring transactions, the card data is stored with our assigned PCI DSS-certified payment provider. In this respect, the legal basis for the processing is Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR (performance of contract).

Blacklane itself does not store credit card data or only in abbreviated form for analysis purposes or to prevent fraud. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

Card payments are provided by the payment service provider Braintree. The privacy policy for the use of the Braintree service can be found at: [](https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal)[https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal](https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal).

Information on new security and verification procedures in connection with the so-called Payment Services Directive ("PSD2") can be found at our payment service provider Braintree ([](https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal)[https://www.braintreepayments.com/de/legal](https://www.braintreepayments.com/de/legal)).

In addition to card payment, you can pay for your bookings via PayPal in our mobile apps (Android / iOS). In this case, on the basis of Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR, personal data such as the e-mail address of your PayPal account and information about your mobile device (e.g. Device ID) will be transmitted by us to PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg, for the purpose of fulfilling the contract. For more information on data processing by PayPal, please visit: [](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)[https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

### [](#10.2-fraud-prevention)10.2 Fraud Prevention

To ensure that a payment instrument is used by its rightful owner and to prevent fraud, IP addresses, e-mail addresses, payment data and card information may be transmitted to one or more external fraud prevention service providers. This transmission may also contain additional personal data. The external fraud prevention service providers process these personal data on behalf of Blacklane. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane).

Blacklane currently uses the service provider Ravelin (Ravelin Technology Ltd., 5th Floor, 174 - 180 Old Street, London, England, EC1V 9BP) for fraud prevention purposes. For more information about Ravelin's privacy practices, please visit [](https://www.ravelin.com/privacy-policy)[https://www.ravelin.com/privacy-policy](https://www.ravelin.com/privacy-policy).

In the course of the authentication of the cardholder, it may also be necessary for individual transactions that Blacklane requires a copy of an additional identification document (e.g. identity card, passport, drivers’ licence) or a copy of the credit card. Blacklane will ask you to black out any data that is not required (e.g. the credit card number except the last four digits). In this respect, the legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR (fulfilment of contract), your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR) and our legitimate interest (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR).

[](#a-id-communicationwithblacklane)11\. Communication with Blacklane
---------------------------------------------------------------------

If you contact Blacklane (e.g. by phone, contact form, feedback form, chat, messenger, e-mail or social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter)), the data you provide will be processed to handle your request and to answer your inquiry. The legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR (consent) and Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b GDPR (fulfilment of contract and initiation of contract).

Contact data is also used by Blacklane - pseudonymised or anonymised if possible - to design and improve Blacklane services according to your needs, to identify and eliminate malfunctions and problems of a technical or process-related nature and to prevent illegal use of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). In this respect, the legal basis for the processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 letter f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane).

Blacklane also uses external services and tools, e.g. messenger services or chat support tools, to communicate with the customer. The legal basis for the processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane). Agreements on commissioned data processing exist with the respective providers - where necessary.

In this context, we use Intercom as a communication medium, either by e-mail or by messages within our products. The Intercom Messenger apps and apps in inbox products can also give you access to other third-party applications such as Stripe. You should consult the privacy notices of these third parties for more information about how they use your personal information. As part of our service agreements, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information about you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social networking sites and physical addresses, to improve your user experience. For more information about Intercom's privacy practices, please visit [](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy)[https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy).

Blacklane also offers customers different feedback channels, also via external platforms. Such customer feedback is also used to process your request and also - if possible pseudonymized or anonymized - to design and improve Blacklane Services according to your needs, to recognize and eliminate malfunctions and problems of a technical or process-related nature and to prevent illegal use of Blacklane Services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). The legal basis for the data processing is, if you have separately and explicitly agreed, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR (consent) and otherwise Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane). With the respective providers of feedback tools there are again - as far as necessary - agreements on commissioned data processing. The respective feedback tool may contain additional information about which data is collected and in which way data is processed.

[](#a-id-emailadvertisingnewsletter)12\. E-mail Advertising, Newsletter
-----------------------------------------------------------------------

If you have agreed to receiving advertising or if Blacklane otherwise has the right, we will use your customer data to send you personalized advertising or general newsletters. The following data is mainly affected: Form of address, name, e-mail address. The purpose of the data processing is for Blacklane to inform you regarding current offers and to draw attention to features of Blacklane services.

E-mail advertising and newsletters may contain pixels. In this case, a graphic file is inserted into the e-mail sent in HTML format, based on which a statistical evaluation may be carried out. By using pixels, Blacklane can detect whether and when e-mails have been opened and links contained therein clicked. The legal base for the data processing is, insofar as you have separately and expressly consented, Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (consent) and otherwise Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest) in conjunction with Section 7 Paragraph 3 of the German Act Against Unfair Competition (UWG).

Blacklane has the right, in context of legal permission according to Section 7 Paragraph 3 UWG, to use the e-mail address, which you have provided regarding a chargeable booking, to directly advertise its own, similar products or services. If you do not wish to receive advertising from Blacklane for similar products or services, you may at any time revoke the corresponding use of your e-mail address without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs in accordance with the base tariffs. To this end, you can use the unsubscribe link contained in any mail or you can write an e-mail to us using the above-mentioned e-mail addresses (see [section 2](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#NameandContactInformationoftheController)).

[](#a-id-involvementofdataprocessorsbyblacklane)13\. Involvement of Data Processors by Blacklane
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

As far as Blacklane involves third parties in its data processing, e.g. technical service providers or other Blacklane subsidiaries, this is always done on behalf of Blacklane and only if these processors offer sufficient guarantees that suitable technical and organisational measures are carried out in such a way that the processing is in accordance with the data protection requirements, in particular Art. 28 GDPR, and guarantees the protection of the rights of the data subject. If processors are located in third countries, the data protection requirements for the transfer pursuant to Art. 44 et seq. GDPR are complied with in each case. As a rule, the appropriate guarantees in third countries are established by means of an adequacy decision (Art. 45 para. 3 GDPR) or the agreement of standard contractual clauses (see Art. 46 para. 2 c) GDPR in conjunction with Art. 93 para. 2 GDPR).

[](#a-id-rightsofdatasubjects)14 Rights of Data Subjects
--------------------------------------------------------

If your personal data is processed by Blacklane, you are the data subject (Art. 4 No. 1 GDPR). As the data subject, you have the following rights in relation to the personal data affecting you:

### [](#14.1-right-to-information-art.-15-gdpr)14.1 Right to information (Art. 15 GDPR)

The data subject has the right to obtain a confirmation from the controller as to whether personal data is processed; if this is the case, they have a right of information about this personal data and further information on the data processing.

### [](#14.2-right-to-rectification-art.-16-gdpr)14.2 Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)

The data subject has the right to obtain from the controller without undue delay the rectification or completion of inaccurate personal data.

### [](#14.3-right-to-erasure-art.-17-gdpr)14.3 Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)

The data subject has the right to demand from the controller the erasure of personal data without undue delay and the controller is obliged to erase personal data without undue delay, provided the data is no longer required, the data subject revokes their consent or lodges an objection to the processing, the personal data was processed unlawfully or there is otherwise a ground for erasure within the meaning of Art. 17 GDPR and the controller does not have the right to object to erasure.

### [](#14.4-right-to-the-restriction-of-data-processing-art.-18-gdpr)14.4 Right to the restriction of data processing (Art. 18 GDPR)

The data subject has the right to demand from the controller the restriction of processing when one of the conditions mentioned in Art. 18 GDPR applies, namely the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject or the processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data.

### [](#14.5-right-to-objection-art.-21-gdpr)14.5 Right to objection (Art. 21 GDPR)

Insofar as the data processing is based on a legitimate interest from our side (Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. f GDPR) or is direct advertising, the data subject has at any time the right to lodge an objection to the processing of personal data affecting them for the reasons mentioned in Art. 21 GDPR. The controller will then no longer process the personal data, unless they can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject or the processing serves for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

### [](#14.6-right-to-data-portability-art.-20-gdpr)14.6 Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)

The data subject has the right within the meaning of Art. 20 GDPR to receive the personal data, which they have provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit this data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data has been provided.

### [](#14.7-right-to-lodge-a-complaint-art.-77-gdpr)14.7 Right to lodge a complaint (Art. 77 GDPR)

Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, every data subject has the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority according to Art. 77 GDPR.

### [](#14.8-revocation-of-consent-art.-7-para.-4-gdpr)14.8 Revocation of consent (Art. 7 para. 4 GDPR)

If the data processing is based on the consent of a data subject, the data subject has the right to revoke his or her consent at any time. You can do this by sending an e-mail to: [dataprotection@blacklane.com](mailto:dataprotection@blacklane.com). The revocation of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation.

[](#a-id-automateddecisions)15\. Automated decisions
----------------------------------------------------

In the case of Blacklane, you are only subject to an automated decision process (see Art. 22 GDPR) in exceptional cases if you re-enter a payment method via which a payment has already previously failed or when current indications justify the suspicion that it is a fraudulent booking. In these cases, your request to book a ride with Blacklane will be refused. Such an automatic decision is required to conclude the contract (Art. 22 Paragraph 2 lit a GDPR). The data subject has the option of contacting us using the mentioned contact data (see [section 2](https://www.blacklane.com/en/privacy-policy/#NameandContactInformationoftheController)) in order to have an explanation or an intervention by a person or to express their point of view.

[](#a-id-dataerasureandstorageduration)16\. Data Erasure and Storage Duration
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

We will erase your personal data as soon as the legal basis for its processing lapses. However, legal bases may also exist in parallel or a new one may intervene with the lapsing of a legal basis, such as for example the duty to store determined data to fulfill a legal retention obligation (e.g. according to commercial or tax law).

[](#a-id-amendmentorupdateofthisprivacypolicy)17\. Amendment or Update of this Privacy Policy
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Blacklane reserves the right to update or amend this privacy policy at any time without giving reasons, as far as this should become necessary, e. g. due to developments in legislation, jurisdiction or regulatory actions or due to further technical developments.

Issued: March 23, 2022.

[](#a-id-blacklanecookiepolicy)Blacklane Cookie Policy
======================================================

Blacklane uses cookies, pixels or similar technologies (e.g. by means of tags, web beacons or gifs). These are small files which are stored on your end device so that we can recognize you or collect information better when you use Blacklane websites or a Blacklane app.

Cookies may be distinguished according to their operating life between session cookies, which are deleted automatically after ending the browser session or permanent cookies, which are stored beyond the individual browser session and enable subsequent recognition of the end device. A distinction is also made between Blacklane’s own cookies and those of third parties.

You may prevent the storage of cookies at any time using your browser settings or delete any cookies present. However, this may mean that some functions of Blacklane services may not be available or available only to a limited extent. The storage duration is different depending on the cookie and can be inspected in your browser.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using cookies, pixels and similar technologies is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a (consent) and lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

In the context of your visit, Blacklane will set the required cookies, which are technically necessary, to improve functionality or make the use of Blacklane services more user-friendly. This concerns, for example,

* Your identification and authentication,
* Storage and user preferences and settings (e.g. language settings), which you have made,
* the inclusion of information already provided so that repeated input of information is not necessary,
* security-related cookies or
* cookies for using multimedia players

Blacklane also uses its own cookies in order to analyze and improve the usage of Blacklane services, to detect and remedy interruptions and problems of a technical or process-related nature and to prevent illegal usage of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). Evaluations by Blacklane take place in pseudonymized or anonymized form as far as is possible.

Additionally, Blacklane uses its own cookies, pixels or similar technologies or those originating from advertising partners (e.g. search engine providers, advertising networks or distribution partners) in order to improve Blacklane services or to measure, evaluate, design and improve advertising measures. Blacklane uses different analysis tools in this regard. In this respect, an evaluation by Blacklane takes place in pseudonymized or anonymized form as far as is possible.

The following cookies, pixels and similar technologies may be used in the context of Blacklane’s services:

### [](#a-id-adjust)Adjust

Blacklane uses the provider Adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 37A, 10405 Berlin, Germany (“Adjust”).

Adjust provides mobile analytics and attribution services for app providers. As part of these services, Adjust may collect, process and use certain data from the users of these apps (jointly the “end user” or “you”) and at Blacklane’s instruction.

The Adjust SDK and APIs (jointly the “Adjust technology”) may collect and use some of the following data from you as the end user:

* Hashed IP address mobile identifiers such as the advertising ID for iOS (IDFA),
* Google Advertising ID or similar mobile identifiers,
* Installation and initial opening of an app on your mobile device,
* Your interaction within an app (e.g. in-app purchases, registration),
* Information on which adverts you have viewed or clicked.

Adjust uses the collected data to provide mobile analytics and attribution services for their customers and thereby enables Blacklane to track its marketing performance to compare them with their campaigns and to understand how you use the Blacklane app. Adjust also enables Blacklane to track your interactions in their apps in real time in order to see how you behave during your entire time using the app. The collected data is thus used to analyze the performance of marketing campaigns and to provide Blacklane with performance reports. Adjust does not combine the collected data with other data, which would allow Adjust to personally identify you.

You can find more information on Adjust Technology here: [](https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/)[https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/)

If you would like to opt out of the Adjust Technology tracking, please open the following page: [](https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/)[https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/](https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/), please choose the device you would like to turn off and enter your device identifier. We will then immediately remove the behavior tracking from apps using our technology. If you have any questions regarding this opt-out, please send an e-mail to [privacy@adjust.com](mailto:privacy@adjust.com) or [legal@adjust.com](mailto:legal@adjust.com) and Adjust will get back to you as soon as possible.

### [](#a-id-adnxs)Adnxs (AppNexus)

Blacklane uses AppNexus, c/o Xandr, 28 W, 23rd Street, New York, New York, 10010, USA.

AppNexus is a company that provides technology, data and analytics to help companies buy and sell online display advertising. AppNexus runs the analytics and advertising platform adnxs.

AppNexus uses cookies and web beacons to build groups of users (segments) that are used to target advertising. Web beacons may also appear on these websites and work in conjunction with the cookies to identify the types of pages a browser is visiting. It is also possible that web beacons may be included in advertising that is using the AppNexus service to provide data about the success of the adverts and whether browsers who clicked on adverts then went on to buy anything.

Information that may be tracked about a browser include:

* a unique identifier (so a browser can be recognised when it appears on another website using AppNexus' services).
* what adverts the browser has seen.
* what page the browser was on when they saw the advert.
* when the browser saw the advert.
* whether the advert has been clicked or not.
* what type of pages the browser has visited (to build up an idea of what content might be used).
* IP Address (to infer location).

You can find more information on AppNexus Technology here: [](https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de)[https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de](https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de) If you would like to opt out of the AppNexus Technology tracking, please open the following page: [](https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de#choices)[https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de#choices](https://www.appnexus.com/corporate-privacy-policy-de#choices). If you have any questions regarding this opt-out, please send an e-mail to [privacy@appnexus.com](mailto:privacy@appnexus.com) and AppNexus will get back to you as soon as possible.

### [](#a-id-bing)Bing Ads

Blacklane uses the online advertising program, Bing Ads and as part of Bing Ads, Bings Ads Conversion Tracking from the Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA (“Microsoft”).

In the case of Bing Ads, cookies are set on your computer if you access our website via a Microsoft Bing advert. We and Microsoft Bing can thereby recognize that someone has clicked on an advert, was directed to our website and reached a previously-determined conversion page. We only find out the total number of users who have clicked on a Bing advert and were then taken to the conversion page. This tool allows us to determine the effectiveness of our advertisements. According to Microsoft, no personal information concerning the identity of the user is disclosed.

If you would not like to participate in tracking, you may block its usage by deactivating the cookie for conversion tracking in your internet browser in the user settings.

You can find further information concerning Bing Ads and the relevant data processing using the following internet addresses. [](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/user-safety-and-privacy-policies)[https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/user-safety-and-privacy-policies](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/user-safety-and-privacy-policies) [](https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement)[https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement)

### [](#a-id-doubleclick)DoubleClick

Blacklane uses DoubleClick by Google, a service from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

DoubleClick by Google uses cookies to present to you adverts that are relevant for you. If you visit our website, a pseudonymous identification number (ID) is assigned to your browser in the form of cookies to verify which adverts were displayed in your browser and which adverts were accessed. The cookies do not contain personal information. The use of the DoubleClick cookies allows Google and its partner websites only to place adverts based on previous visits to our or to other websites on the internet (so-called retargeting). The information generated by the cookies is transferred by Google for evaluation to a server in the USA and stored there. Data is transferred by Google to third parties only based on legal regulations or as part of contract data processing. Google will not combine your data with other data collected by Google.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can prevent this by changing the settings in your browser software or deactivating DoubleClick cookies using the following link (“opt out”): [](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)[http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-facebookcustomaudiencesundimpressions)Facebook (Custom Audiences und Impressions)

Blacklane uses the service, Facebook Custom Audiences and Facebook Impressions operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). The controller for the data processing in Europe for Facebook is Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland.

If you visit our websites, you will be recognized via the use of cookies. It therefore can be measured when and how often you return and use Blacklane. Based on this information, we can display advertising to you in a targeted manner via Facebook. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA. Facebook Impressions allows us to measure how often adverts appear on your screen. We can therefore draw conclusions concerning the effectiveness of our advertising measures.

You can find additional information concerning Facebook’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)[https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) [](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)[https://www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php) [](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/)[https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/)

If you do not want Facebook to target you with advertising, you can adjust the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

### [](#a-id-googleads)Google Ads (former Google AdWords Conversion Tracker)

Blacklane uses the online advertising program “Google AdWords” and as part of Google AdWords, the conversion tracking of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”).

We use the Google AdWords service to bring attention to our services with the help of adverts (so-called Google AdWords) on external websites. The cookie for conversion tracking is placed when a user clicks on an AdWords advert placed by Google. Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer system. These cookies generally become invalid after 30 days and do not allow personal identification. If you visited a certain site and if the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google can recognize that you have clicked on the advert and were taken to this site. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. The collected information by use of the conversion cookie serves to generate conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. The customers find out the total number of users who have clicked on their advert and were taken to a page provided with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information by means of which users can be personally identified. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA.

If you would not like to participate in tracking, you may block its usage by deactivating the Google conversion tracking cookie in your internet browser under user settings. You will then not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-googleanalytics)Google Analytics

Blacklane uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

Google Analytics uses cookies which are stored on your computer and which enable an analysis of your usage of the website. The information generated by the cookie concerning your usage of this website (including the abbreviated IP address) is generally transferred to a Google server in the US and stored there. Blacklane uses Google Analytics exclusively with the extension “\_anonymizeIp()” which ensures anonymization of the IP address by abbreviation and excludes direct reference to persons. Using this extension, Google will abbreviate your IP address beforehand within Member States of the European Union or within other signatories to the agreement of the European Economic Area. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate your usage of the website to compile reports concerning the website activities and to render other services to us, which are associated with the website usage and the internet usage. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not associated with other Google data.

If you do not agree with the use of Google Analytics, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via [](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)[https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-googledynamicremarketing)Google Dynamic Remarketing

Blacklane uses the service, Google Dynamic Remarketing from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

When you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie will be stored on your device, which allows you to be recognized when you access a website which belongs to the Google advertising network. Ad banners may be displayed to you on these websites which relate to previously viewed content. Google does not collect personal data during this process. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA.

If you do not agree with Remarketing, you can adapt the settings for cookies in your browser or deactivate the function at [](https://adssettings.google.com/)[https://adssettings.google.com/](https://adssettings.google.com/).

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-googlefirebase)Google Firebase

Blacklane uses the platform, Google Firebase from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

Google Firebase is a web app and mobile app development platform which, in addition to development services not relevant to data protection, also provides services relevant to data protection such as analysis tools and interest-based advertising.

When you visit our website on a tablet or smartphone, cookies and related technologies are used to enable part of the services provided by Firebase. The data volume primarily results from measured user behaviors on the website and technical data. The data collected will be stored and processed in the US.

If you do not agree with the collection of data by Google Firebase, you can adapt the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

You can find additional information concerning Google and Firebase data protection provisions using the internet addresses below. The last link includes a table with the explicit data processing measures: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-googlefonts)Google Fonts

In order to display fonts, Blacklane uses Web Fonts from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

When you access a website, you browser loads the required web fonts in your browser to correctly display the text and fonts. To this end, your browser connects to Google whereby Google finds out that our websites were accessed via your IP address.

Google Fonts are used in the interest of consistent and appealing display of the Blacklane websites. If your browser does not support Google Fonts or Web Fonts, a standard font will be used by your end device.

You can find additional information concerning Google Fonts and Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](https://fonts.google.com/)[https://fonts.google.com/](https://fonts.google.com/) [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)

### [](#a-id-googlerecaptcha)Google reCAPTCHA

Blacklane uses the service, Google reCAPTCHA from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

Google reCAPTCHA serves to determine, during the booking process of a ride, whether the booking was made by a human or whether the supposed customer is an improperly used computer (“Bot”). Google makes this distinction using a small test, so-called reCAPTCHA (\_\_C\_\_ompletely \_\_A\_\_utomated \_\_P\_\_ublic \_\_T\_\_uring test to tell \_\_C\_\_omputers and \_\_H\_\_umans \_\_A\_\_part). In order to confirm a booking, you must for example check a box or sort images according to a certain rule. It can then be discerned whether the visitor is a computer or a human, Google uses data such as IP address, browser, screen resolution, click behavior and, if necessary, other required data (e.g. cookies). The collected data is transferred to a Google server in the US for processing.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can adapt the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)[https://www.cookiechoices.org/](https://www.cookiechoices.org/)

### [](#a-id-googletagmanagerandconversionlink)Google Tag Manager and Conversion Link

Blacklane uses Google Tag Manager, a tool from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”) to manage website tags via an interface.

The Google Tag Manager implements tags or markers. The Google Tag Manager triggers other tags, which in turn may collect data.

You can find more information about Google's privacy policy at the following internet addresses: [](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy)[http://www.google.de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/policies/privacy) [](https://policies.google.com/technologies/product-privacy?hl=de)[https://policies.google.com/technologies/product-privacy?hl=de](https://policies.google.com/technologies/product-privacy?hl=de)

The tag "conversion link" is used to store click data in own cookies which are linked to Blacklane domains. Conversions, i.e. planned behaviour, can be recorded by this function. Further information can be found here: [](https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/7549390?hl=de)[https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/7549390?hl=de](https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/7549390?hl=de)

### [](#a-id-hotjar)Hotjar

Blacklane uses the analysis tool Hotjar from Hotjar Ltd, , Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta (“Hotjar”).

When you visit our website, in addition to technical master data and cookies, user mouse movements are in particular assessed to create so-called “heat maps”. This information allows Blacklane to design the website to be faster and more customer-friendly. Personal data is hidden in this process and thus not collected separately.

If you do not agree with the approach of Hotjar, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via [](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out)[https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

You can find additional information concerning Hotjar’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy)[https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy)

### [](#a-id-intercom)Intercom

Blacklane uses services of Intercom, Inc., 55 2nd Street, 4th Fl., San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, to better understand your use of our services.

We provide Intercom, Inc. with a limited amount of your information (e.g., registration date and some personal information such as your e-mail address). We use Intercom to collect data for analysis purposes when you visit our website or use our product. As a data processor, Intercom, at our direction, analyses your use of our website and/or product and tracks our relationship through cookies and similar technologies so that we can improve our service to you. For further information about the use of cookies by Intercom, please visit [](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy)[https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy). We can also use Intercom as a communication medium, either by e-mail or by messages within our products. The Intercom Messenger apps and apps in inbox products can also give you access to other third-party applications such as Stripe. You should consult the privacy notices of these third parties for more information about how they use your personal information. As part of our service agreements, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information about you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social networking sites and physical addresses, to improve your user experience. For more information about Intercom's privacy practices, please visit [](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy)[https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy).

The services of Intercom are subject to the Terms of Use of Intercom, which can be found at [](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms)[https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms). If you wish to opt-out of having this information collected or transmitted by Intercom, please contact us.

### [](#a-id-linkedinmarketingsolutions)LinkedIn Marketing Solutions

Blacklane uses the service LinkedIn Marketing Solutions operated by the LinkedIn Corporation., 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“LinkedIn”).

When you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie is stored on the device of the user. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and collects certain usage data. If you then visit LinkedIn, advertising is displayed to you based on the collected data. The data stored and processed in the USA does not make you identifiable as a person.

If you do not want to participate in tracking, you can deactivate the storage of LinkedIn cookies in your browser setting or via [](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out)[https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out).

You can find additional information concerning LinkedIn’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?_l=de_DE)[https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?\_l=de\_DE](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?_l=de_DE)

### [](#a-id-mailchimp)MailChimp

In order to send e-mails, Blacklane uses the e-mail service MailChimp provided by The Rocket Science Group LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Avenue NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA (“MailChimp”).

If you register for our newsletter or provide us with your e-mail address as part of registration, the data required for such purpose (e-mail address, language, country) will be transmitted to MailChimp in the USA and stored there. In addition to simply sending e-mails, MailChimp provides different analysis options to inform us of whether, when and where the distributed emails are opened, used or rejected. To this end, MailChimp uses, amongst other things, cookies and similar technologies.

If you do not agree with receiving e-mails and newsletters, you can unsubscribe at any time using the “unsubscribe” button which is present in every communication. You may refuse the use of cookies in your browser settings.

You can find additional information concerning MailChimp’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: [](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)[https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) [](https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/)[https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/)

### [](#a-id-mixpanel)Mixpanel

Blacklane uses the services of Mixpanel Inc., 405 Howard Street, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Mixpanel”).

Mixpanel uses cookies or similar technologies to automatically collect certain information. The aim of this approach is for example to optimize web services, marketing activities and customer experiences and to filter out the popularity of individual website areas.

Mixpanel also uses pixel tags which are also designated as clear gifs, web beacons or web bugs. In this case, they are small graphic images with a clear identifier, similar to cookies, which are used to track online movements of web users. Unlike cookies, pixel tags are invisibly embedded into websites and also allow Mixpanel to send e-mails and determine whether these e-mails were opened. It is thus intended to ensure that only messages are sent which are of interest to users. Mixpanel does not link any pixel tag information with personal user data.

Additionally, Mixpanel can also record non-personal data (e.g. information concerning the device type used) of the user’s mobile devices when a corresponding application is downloaded.

Mixpanel uses interest-related advertising which can be turned off by users at [](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)[http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). The data collection by cookies can be deactivated by adapting your browser’s cookie settings accordingly or at [](https://mixpanel.com/optout/)[https://mixpanel.com/optout/](https://mixpanel.com/optout/).

You can find more information in the Mixpanel privacy policy: [](https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/)[https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/](https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/)

### [](#a-id-nexmo)Nexmo

Blacklane uses the communication tool Nexmo with the data protection contact “Vonage Limited”, 15 Bonhill Street, 3rd Floor London, England EC2A 4DN, Great Britain. Nexmo offers a communications solution for the provision of end-to-end communication via voice, video, text (especially SMS), mobile applications and collaboration tools. This also includes various analysis options. For more information, please refer to the Nexmo or Vonage privacy policy: [](https://www.vonage.com/privacy-policy)[https://www.vonage.com/privacy-policy](https://www.vonage.com/privacy-policy)

### [](#a-id-optimizely)Optimizely

Blacklane uses the analysis tool, Optimizely from the company, Optimizely Inc., 681 Howard St. Suite 100 I San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Optimizely”).

When you visit the website, data such as cookies and/or device identifiers, IP addresses, interaction times, usage times and language settings are collected to enable in particular an analysis of responses to new features and changes on the website. The data stored and processed in the US is not personal data.

If you do not agree with the approach of Optimizely, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via [](https://www.optimizely.com/de/legal/opt-out/)[https://www.optimizely.com/de/legal/opt-out/](https://www.optimizely.com/de/legal/opt-out/).

You can find additional information concerning Optimizely’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://www.optimizely.com/de/privacy/)[https://www.optimizely.com/de/privacy/](https://www.optimizely.com/de/privacy/)

### [](#a-id-outbrain)Outbrain Pixel / OutBrain Amplify

Blacklane uses the services, Outbrain Pixel and Outbrain Amplify from Outbrain UK Ltd., 5 New Bridge Street, London, EC4V 6JA, UK (“Outbrain”).

When you visit our website, an individual ID in the form of cookies is stored on your device. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and collects your usage data. Based on the content accessed by you on this and any Outbrain partner websites, recommendations can now be made to you for additional possible interesting content. Personal data is not stored to do so.

If you do not agree with the approach of Outbrain, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via [](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/#advertising_behavioral_targeting)[https://www.outbrain.com/legal/#advertising\_behavioral\_targeting](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/#advertising_behavioral_targeting).

You can find additional information concerning Outbrain’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy)[https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy)

### [](#a-id-polyfill)Polyfill

Blacklane uses the service, Polyfill from Financial Times Ltd., One Southwark Bridge Road, London, UK (“Polyfill”). When you visit our website, data is collected concerning your browser (version etc.), your internet access (IP address) and the URL which uses the services of Polyfill. This data allows Polyfill to detect any discrepancies between your current browser version and the technical condition of our website. In order to still display a seamless and fully functional version of our website via your browser, Polyfill uses so-called “polyfills”, code components, which close the technical gaps and make the website usable.

No personal data is collected during this process.

You can find additional information concerning Polyfill’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://polyfill.io/v3/privacy-policy/)[https://polyfill.io/docs/privacy-policy](https://polyfill.io/docs/privacy-policy)

### [](#a-id-raygun)Raygun

Blacklane uses Raygun, L7, 59 Courtenay Place, Te Aro, Wellington 6011, New Zealand.

Raygun is integrated with the Blacklane websites and monitors their performance. This enables the evaluation of crashes and other errors, whereby the IP-address and geolocation are collected. Information on app crashes is kept for up to six months.

For more information, please refer to Raygun’s privacy policy [(](https://raygun.com/privacy)[https://raygun.com/privacy](https://raygun.com/privacy)).

### [](#a-id-rudderstack)Rudderstack

Blacklane uses RudderStack 96 S. Park Street San Francisco 94107.

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies; Usage Data; email address; phone number; Universally unique identifier (UUID); Data communicated while using the service; first name; last name; company name.

You can find more information here: [](https://www.rudderstack.com/cookie-policy/)[https://www.rudderstack.com/cookie-policy/](https://www.rudderstack.com/cookie-policy/) and [](https://www.rudderstack.com/privacy-policy/?no_markup=false&from_cookie_policy=true)[https://www.rudderstack.com/privacy-policy/?no\_markup=false&from\_cookie\_policy=true](https://www.rudderstack.com/privacy-policy/?no_markup=false&from_cookie_policy=true) And to opt out: [](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/)[https://optout.networkadvertising.org/](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/)

Any other request to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner by contacting them via email to privacy@rudderstack.com.

### [](#a-id-salesforce)Salesforce

Blacklane uses services from Salesforce.com, Inc., The Landmark at One Market, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Salesforce”).

You can find additional information in the Salesforce privacy policy: [](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/)[https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/) [](https://www.salesforce.com/company/disclosure/)[https://www.salesforce.com/company/disclosure/](https://www.salesforce.com/company/disclosure/)

### [](#a-id-sendgrid)SendGrid

For the sending of e-mails, Blacklane uses the e-mail provider, SendGrid from the company SendGrid Inc., 1801 California Street, Suite 500, Denver, CO 80202, USA (“SendGrid”).

If you provide us with your e-mail address as part of the registration, the data required for such purpose (e-mail address, language, country) will be transmitted to SendGrid in the USA and stored there. In addition to simply sending e-mail, SendGrid provides different analysis options to inform us of whether, when and where the distributed newsletter are opened, used or rejected. To this end, SendGrid uses, amongst other things, cookies and similar technologies.

If you do not agree with receiving e-mails not required for the service, such as e.g. the newsletter, you can unsubscribe at any time using the “unsubscribe” button which is present in every communication. You may refuse the use of cookies in your browser settings.

You can find additional information concerning SendGrid’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy)[https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy)

### [](#a-id-snowplow)Snowplow

Blacklane uses Snowplow, a tool of Snowplow Analytics Limited, 32-38 Scrutton Street, EC2A 4RQ London, United Kingdom ("Snowplow"). Snowplow will store a cookie on your device with the following content: non-refundable random combination number ("hash"), time, URL of the page accessed, URL of the previous website (referrer), content of the cookies, IDs, anonymized IP address, version and port of the browser, operating system. Snowplow is embedded in Blacklane's own server infrastructure, which means that the data analysed with it does not leave the Blacklane servers.

For more information, please see Snowplow's privacy policy: [](https://snowplowanalytics.com/privacy-policy/)[https://snowplowanalytics.com/privacy-policy/](https://snowplowanalytics.com/privacy-policy/)

### [](#a-id-twitter)Twitter Advertising

Blacklane uses the service, Twitter Ads operated by the company, Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”).

If you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie is stored on your device. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and records certain usage data. If you then visit Twitter, advertising is displayed to you based on the data transmitted to the USA. Twitter does not collect any data which makes you identifiable as a person.

If you do not want Twitter to target you with advertising, you can adapt your browser’s cookie settings or deactivate the function at [](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads)[https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads).

You can find additional information concerning Twitter’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: [](https://twitter.com/de/privacy)[https://twitter.com/de/privacy](https://twitter.com/de/privacy)

### [](#a-id-xandr)Xandr

Blacklane uses Xandr, 28 W, 23rd Street, New York, New York, 10010, USA.

Xandr is a company that provides technology, data and analytics to help companies buy and sell online display advertising.

Xandr uses cookies and web beacons to build groups of users (segments) that are used to target advertising. Web beacons may also appear on these websites and work in conjunction with the cookies to identify the types of pages a browser is visiting. It is also possible that web beacons may be included in advertising that is using the Xandr service to provide data about the success of the adverts and whether browsers who clicked on adverts then went on to buy anything.

Information that may be tracked about a browser include:

* the type of browser you use, browser language, browser settings, and cookie information. This may include data about you related to bid requests an ad impressions, collected when we decide to show you an ad on a Digital Property and when we deliver an ad.
* Information about your device including device operating system version, connection type, device make, device model, device Identifiers such as your IDFA or AAID, and the IP address from which the device accesses a client’s Digital Property.
* Location information, including precise location information when location services have been enabled for an app on your device that has integrated our technology or that sends that information to our Platform.
* Information about your activity on a Digital Property such as browsing history, viewing history, search history and information regarding an individual’s interaction with an internet website, app, or advertisement, including the time web pages or apps were visited or used, including in-game or online viewing activity (e.g., videos viewed, pages viewed).
* Inferences or audience segmentation derived from Platform Data, such as individual profiles, preferences, characteristics, and behaviors.
* Information about ads served, viewed or clicked on, including the type of ad, where the ad was served, whether you clicked on it and whether you visited the advertiser’s website or downloaded the advertiser’s app.
* Information about your internet service including information about which internet service provider is used by you.

You can find more information on Xandr Technology here: [](https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/)[https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/](https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/) If you would like to opt out of the Xandr Technology tracking, you can find more information on the following page: [](https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/)[https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/](https://www.xandr.com/privacy/platform-privacy-policy/). To review your opt in status or learn more about interest-based advertising, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page, the DAA’s WebChoice tool or the DAAC’s WebChoices tool. If you have any questions regarding the opt-out, please send an e-mail to legal@xandr.com and Xandr will get back to you as soon as possible.

Issued: December 3, 2020.
